[This talk contains graphic language and descriptions of sexual violence]
【本演讲包含粗口和对性暴力的描述】
[Viewer discretion is advised]
【建议观众谨慎观看】
"Ashley Judd, stupid fucking slut.
“艾什莉·贾德，你这个愚蠢的荡妇。”
"You can't sue someone for calling them a cunt."
“你不能因为别人说脏话就起诉他们。”
"If you can't handle the Internet, fuck off, whore."
“你要是受不了互联网，就滚蛋，婊子。”
"I wish Ashley Judd would die a horrible death.
“我希望艾什莉·贾德死得很难看。
She is the absolute worst."
她绝不是什么好东西。”
"Ashley Judd, you're the reason women shouldn't vote."
“艾什莉·贾德，因为你的存在，女人才不该有选举权。”
"'Twisted' is such a bad movie,
“《非常命案》太烂了，
I don't even want to rape it."
我都懒得强暴它。”
"Whatever you do,
“无论你做什么，
don't tell Ashley Judd. She'll die alone with a dried out vagina."
不要告诉阿什利·贾德，她会在性饥渴中孤零零死掉。”
"If I had to fuck an older woman,
“如果我非得干一个老女人，
oh my God,
我的天哪，
I would fuck the shit out of Ashley Judd,
我一定会选阿什利·贾德，
that bitch is hot af.
那婊子太火辣了。
The unforgivable shit I would do to her."
我会狠狠蹂躏她的。”
Online misogyny is a global gender rights tragedy,
网上厌女症已经在全球范围内对性别公平造成破坏，
and it is imperative that it ends.
这必须得到制止。
(Applause)
（掌声）
Girls' and women's voices,
女孩和妇女的声音，
and our allies' voices are constrained in ways
以及我们的同盟的声音很多时候被限制了，
that are personally, economically,
这些打压会带来了个人层面、经济上、
professionally and politically damaging.
专业和政治上的负面影响。
And when we curb abuse,
如果我们能够阻止欺凌，
we will expand freedom.
我们就能推动自由。
I am a Kentucky basketball fan,
我是肯塔基篮球队的粉丝，
so on a fine March day last year,
所以在去年三月某一天，
I was doing one of the things I do best:
我正在做我最擅长的事情：
I was cheering for my Wildcats.
我为我喜欢的队员喝彩。
The daffodils were blooming,
水仙花正在盛开。
but the referees were not blowing the whistle when I was telling them to.
但是当我让裁判员吹哨时，他们并没有吹。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Funny, they're very friendly to me before the opening tip,
好玩的是，他们在开场的时候还是挺友好的，
but they really ignore me during the game.
但是比赛开始之后就无视我了。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Three of my players were bleeding, so I did the next best thing ...
我方三名队员受伤流血，于是我做了我第二擅长的事情：
I tweeted.
我发了推特。
[@ArkRazorback dirty play can kiss my team's free throw making a --
[阿肯色震圈的肮脏的打法可以见鬼去了，我队应有罚球权，
@KySportsRadio @marchmadness @espn Bloodied 3 players so far.]
已造成三位我方球员受伤。]
It is routine for me to be treated in the ways I've already described to you.
我演讲一开始向你们展示的那些脏话，我已经司空见惯，
It happens to me every single day
每天我都在社交媒体上面对这些
on social media platforms such as Twitter and Facebook.
不管是在Facebook还是在Twitter上都是如此。
Since I joined Twitter in 2011,
自从我2011年开了推特帐号，
misogyny and misogynists have amply demonstrated
厌女症和厌女分子就充分地表现了
they will dog my every step.
他们会尾随我的每一步。
My spirituality, my faith,
我的精神，我的信念，
being a hillbilly -- I can say that, you can't --
作为乡巴佬——我可以这么说——但是你们不行
all of it is fair game.
所有这些都是攻击目标。
And I have responded to this with various strategies.
我用了各种战术来回击。
I've tried engaging people.
我尝试唤起人们的责任感。
This one guy was sending me hypersexual, nasty stuff,
曾经有一个男人给我发了肮脏下流的性图片，
and there was a girl in his avatar.
而我发现他的头像里有一个小姑娘。
I wrote him back and said ...
我回复他说：
"Is that your daughter?
“那是你女儿么？
I feel a lot of fear that you may think about and talk to women this way."
我非常的担心，你这种看待女性和跟女性交流的方式。”
And he surprised me by saying,
他的回复让我惊讶，
"You know what? You're right. I apologize."
“你知道么？你是对的。我道歉。”
Sometimes people want to be held accountable.
有时候，人们就需要被追究责任。
This one guy was musing to I don't know who
另一个人不知道在和谁说
that maybe I was the definition of a cunt.
也许我就是妈逼的代名词。
I was married to a Scot for 14 years,
我嫁给一个苏格兰人14年了，
so I said, "Cunt means many different things in different countries --
所以我回复说，“妈逼这个词在不同国家有不同含义——
(Laughter)
（笑声）
but I'm pretty sure you epitomize the global standard of a dick."
但是我很确定你这屌丝天下无双。”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
(Applause)
（掌声）
I've tried to rise above it, I've tried to get in the trenches,
我尝试去脱离这些言论我也试着去理解它们，
but mostly I would scroll through these social media platforms
绝大部分时候，我会社交媒体上
with one eye partially closed, trying not to see it,
睁一只眼闭一只眼，试着躲避这些不堪入目的东西，
but you can't make a cucumber out of a pickle.
但覆水难收。
What is seen goes in.
看过就会记得。
It's traumatic.
这就是创伤。
And I was always secretly hoping in some part of me
我一直内心深处渴望有一个我
that what was being said to me and about me wasn't ... true.
能够告诉我这些关于我的言论都不是真的。
Because even I,
因为就算我，
an avowed, self-declared feminist,
一位公然承认的女权主义者，
who worships at the altar of Gloria --
尽管虔诚地信奉着女权信仰，
(Laughter)
（笑声）
internalize the patriarchy.
仍会吸收内化男权思想。
This is really critical.
这点非常重要。
Patriarchy is not boys and men.
因为男权社会不止关乎男孩与男人。
It is a system in which we all participate,
这是一个我们所有人都参与其中的社会系统，
including me.
包括我。
On that particular day, for some reason,
那天，不知为何，
that particular tweet after the basketball game
我在篮球比赛后发送的推特
triggered something called a "cyber mob."
引发了一场网络围攻。
This vitriolic, global outpouring of the most heinous hate speech:
尖酸恶劣的憎恨言论从四面八方涌来，
death threats, rape threats.
包括死亡威胁，强奸威胁。
And don't you know,
而且你知道吗，
when I was sitting at home alone in my nightgown,
当我穿着睡袍独自在家时，
I got a phone call, and it was my beloved former husband,
我接到了我心爱的前夫的电话留言，
and he said on a voice mail,
留言里他说，
"Loved one ...
“亲爱的...
what is happening to you is not OK."
你现在的遭遇是不允容忍的。“
And there was something about him taking a stand for me that night ...
而正是那晚他对我的支持，
that allowed me to take a stand for myself.
鼓励我为自己挺身而出。
And I started to write.
我开始写作，
I started to write about sharing the fact
通过文字告诉外界
that I'm a survivor of all forms of sexual abuse,
我是一位受过各种性侵犯的生还者，
including three rapes.
包括三起强奸。
And the hate speech I get in response to that --
而我也因此收到了更多的憎恨抨击，
these are just some of the comments posted to news outlets.
这些只是媒体报道下的部分言论。
Being told I'm a "snitch" is really fun.
他们说我“专打小报告。”
[Jay: She enjoyed every second of it!!!!!]
［杰伊: 她肯定享受性侵的每一分一秒！］
Audience: Oh, Lord Jesus.
观众：我的天。
Ashley Judd: Thank you, Jesus. May your grace and mercy shine.
感谢主，愿你的恩典和怜悯永远闪耀。
So, I wrote this feminist op-ed, it is entitled,
所以我写了一篇女权专栏，题目是，
"Forget Your Team:
“与球队无关：
It Is Your Online Gender Violence Toward Girls And Women
让网络上对女孩和妇女的性别暴力
That Can Kiss My Righteous Ass."
见鬼去吧。”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
(Applause)
（掌声）
And I did that alone, and I published it alone,
我独自撰写了文章，也独自发表了它，
because my chief advisor said,
因为我的首席顾问曾劝我，
"Please don't,
“请不要，
the rain of retaliatory garbage that is inevitable --
那些不可避免的报复性的回复－－
I fear for you."
我为你感到害怕。“
But I trust girls and I trust women,
但是我相信女孩和妇女们，
and I trust our allies.
我也相信我们的盟友。
It was published, it went viral,
文章发表后得到了广泛的社会关注，
it proves that every single day
这足以证明
online misogyny is a phenomenon endured by us all,
网络厌女观已成为大家每天都得面对的现象，
all over the world,
不管在世界的哪个角落。
and when it is intersectional,
当厌女观与其它歧视心理交汇时，
it is worse.
事态则会更加严峻。
Sexual orientation, gender identity,
性倾向，性别认知，
race, ethnicity, religion --
人种，种族，宗教－－
you name it,
你所能想到的，
it amplifies the violence endured by girls and women,
这扩大了女性们所需要承受的暴力，
and for our younger girls, it is worse.
对年幼的女孩们来说，这更加可怕。
It's clearly traumatizing.
它造成精神创伤显而易见。
Our mental health, our emotional well-being
我们的心理健康和幸福感
are so gravely affected
都受到了严重的影响
because the threat of violence
因为暴力的威胁，
is experienced neurobiologically as violence.
在精神感官上等同于暴力，
The cortisol shoots up, the limbic system gets fired,
皮质醇上升，淋巴系统受压迫，
we lose productivity at work.
工作效率也会降低。
And let's talk about work.
让我们谈谈工作。
Our ability to work is constrained.
我们工作的能力被局限。
Online searches of women applying for jobs reveal nude pictures of them,
在网上搜索女性应聘者的信息时，会跳出受害女性的裸照，
false allegations they have STDs,
对于她们有性传播疾病的虚假指控，
their addresses indicating that they are available for sex
以及她们的住址，暗示着她们能够提供性服务；
with real examples
这是个真实例子：
of people showing up at this house for said sex.
真的有人相信网上传言，上门要求性服务。
Our ability to go to school is impaired.
我们上学的权利受到了压迫。
96 percent of all postings of sexual images of our young people ... girls.
网络上发布的青少年色情照片96%都是女孩们。
Our girls.
我们的女孩们。
Our boys are two to three times more likely -- nonconsensually -- to share images.
未得照片主角同意在网上传播私人照片的男生比女生多出二至三倍。
And I want to say a word about revenge porn.
我也想讲一讲“复仇色情”。
Part of what came out of this tweet
这条推特的部分效应
was my getting connected with allies and other activists
是我与其它的盟友与积极分子取得联系
who are fighting for a safe and free internet.
那些为安全和自由的网络环境而奋斗的人们。
We started something called the Speech Project;
我们启动了叫做“言论项目”这一计划；
curbing abuse, expanding freedom.
抑制欺凌，扩展自由。
And that website provides a critical forum,
网站上提供了一个重要的平台，
because there is no global, legal thing
因为目前还没有一个国际的，法律支持的纲领
to help us figure this out.
来帮助我们解决这个问题。
But we do provide on that website a standardized list of definitions,
我们在网站上提供一系列标准释义,
because it's hard to attack a behavior in the right way
因为你很难有效的去抨击某种行为，
if we're not all sharing a definition of what that behavior is.
如果我们对那种行为的定义不能达成认同。
And I learned that revenge porn is often dangerously misapplied.
我认识到"复仇色情“的概念往往遭到误解。
It is the nonconsensual sharing of an image
它的定义是：这是在未经当事人同意下，蓄意分享一张照片
used tactically to shame and humiliate a girl or woman
以达到羞辱和侮辱女孩或女性的目的，
that attempts to pornography us.
这张照片会试图将我们色情化。
Our natural sexuality is --
我们与生俱来的性感是－－
I don't know about yours -- pretty gorgeous and wonderful.
我不知道你们的怎么样－－非常美丽和美好的。
And my expressing it does not pornography make.
而我将其展示不代表色诱。
(Applause)
（掌声）
So, I have all these resources
所以，我意识到我所拥有的资源，
that I'm keenly aware so many people in the world do not.
很多其他人并没有。
I was able to start the Speech Project with colleagues.
我能够和同事们一起展开了”言论项目“。
I can often get a social media company's attention.
我常常得到社交媒体公司的注意。
I have a wonderful visit to Facebook HQ coming up.
我不久便会访问脸书总部。
Hasn't helped the idiotic reporting standards yet ...
然而这并没有改变愚蠢的举报流程。
I actually pay someone to scrub my social media feeds,
我付钱让别人清理我的社交媒体界面，
attempting to spare my brain
试着让我的大脑
the daily iterations of the trauma of hate speech.
从每天重复的仇恨言论的创伤中脱离。
And guess what?
猜猜发生了什么
I get hate speech for that.
我因此获得了仇恨言论，
"Oh, you live in an echo chamber."
“哦，你住在回音室里。”
Well, guess what?
那么，我跟你说，
Having someone post a photograph of me with my mouth open
有人发布了我张嘴的照片
saying they "can't wait to cum on my face,"
说他们“等不及射在我的脸上”
I have a right to set that boundary.
我有权制定那种界线。
(Applause)
（掌声）
And this distinction between virtual and real is specious
虚拟和现实之间的区别是似是而非的
because guess what --
因为，你猜怎么着，
that actually happened to me once when I was a child,
那条推文的内容我在童年时真的经历过，
and so that tweet brought up that trauma,
所以这条推特引发的性侵创伤，
and I had to do work on that.
我还在努力处理。
But you know what we do? We take all of this hate speech,
但是你知道我们在做什么吗？我们收集所有的仇恨言论，
and we disaggregate it,
然后我们分解它，
and we code it,
我们将他分门别类，
and we give that data
接着我们拥有了这些可分析数据
so that we understand the intersectionality of it:
这样就能理解它的交互特性
when I get porn,
当我收到淫照时
when it's about political affiliation,
哪些内容是攻击我的政治取向？
when it's about age, when it's about all of it.
哪些攻击我的年龄？哪些内容全方位攻击？
We're going to win this fight.
我们将赢得这场战斗。
There are a lot of solutions --
有很多解决办法——
thank goodness.
谢天谢地。
I'm going to offer just a few,
我只会提供一些，
and of course I challenge you to create and contribute your own.
当然，我也要挑战你让你创造并贡献你自己的力量。
Number one: we have to start with digital media literacy,
首先，我们必须从数字化媒体素养开始。
and clearly it must have a gendered lens.
它必须加上性别平权的观点。
Kids, schools, caregivers, parents:
这需要孩子、学校、护理人员、父母的合力培养。
it's essential.
这是至关重要的。
Two ...
第二个办法
shall we talk about our friends in tech?
能否让我们谈谈我们在科技领域的朋友？
Said with dignity and respect,
我要不卑不亢地说：
the sexism in your workplaces must end.
你工作场所内的性别歧视必须结束。
(Applause)
（掌声）
(Cheers)
（欢呼）
EDGE,
事实上
the global standard for gender equality,
达到两性平等的国际标准
is the minimum standard.
是你们最起码要做到的。
And guess what, Silicon Valley?
硅谷，请听好了，
If L'Oréal in India,
如果欧莱雅在印度
in the Philippines, in Brazil
在菲律宾，在巴西
and in Russia can do it,
与在俄罗斯能做到，
you can, too.
你也能做到。
Enough excuses.
别再找借口了。
Only when women have critical mass in every department at your companies,
只有当女性在公司的每个部门成为重要的群体时，
including building platforms from the ground up,
包括在企业各阶层建立发表意见平台，
will the conversations about priorities and solutions change.
秩序和解决方案才有可能改变。
And more love for my friends in tech:
我还有一项对科技行业的朋友们的温馨提示：
profiteering off misogyny in video games must end.
在电子游戏中通过厌女主义盈利的这种行为必须结束。
I'm so tired of hearing you talk to me at cocktail parties --
我听腻了你在鸡尾酒会上跟我说的话——
like you did a couple weeks ago in Aspen --
就像几周前在阿斯彭的时候一样——
about how deplorable #Gamergate was,
你们在谈论女性电玩设计师被性骚扰一事，
when you're still making billions of dollars off games
同时却开发任由玩家虐待女性角色的游戏，
that maim and dump women for sport.
赚上几十亿美元的时候。
Basta! -- as the Italians would say.
"够了！"——就像意大利人说的那样。
Enough.
够了。
(Applause)
（掌声）
Our friends in law enforcement have much to do,
我们的执法部门有很多工作要做。
because we've seen
因为我们知道
that online violence is an extension of in-person violence.
网络暴力是线下暴力的延伸。
In our country,
在美国，
more girls and women have been murdered by their intimate partners
被伴侣谋杀的女孩和妇女
than died on 9/11
比在911恐袭中死去的还要多，
and have died since in Afghanistan and Iraq combined.
比阿富汗、伊拉克战争加起来的死亡人数更多。
And it's not cool to say that,
这样说一点也不好，
but it is true.
但这的确是实情。
We care so much geopolitically about what men are doing over there to women over there ...
我们经常关心身处海外战乱地区的男人对那里的女人会做些什么。
In 2015,
在2015年，
72,828 women used intimate partner violence services in this country.
美國就有72,828名成年女性因家庭暴力而求助。
That is not counting the girls and women and boys who needed them.
这还没有算上需要这种服务的女孩、妇女和男孩。
Law enforcement must be empowered with up-to-date internet technology,
执法部门必须用最新的互联网技术来加强，
the devices and an understanding of these platforms --
像是设备和对这些平台的理解——
how they work.
它们是如何工作的。
The police wanted to be helpful when Amanda Hess called
女记者阿曼达·赫斯向警方反应她收到死亡恐吓推文，
about the death threat she was getting on Twitter,
当时警方也想积极保护她，
but they couldn't really when they said,
结果却是爱莫能助。因为警察问：
"What's Twitter?"
“推特是什么？"
Our legislators must write and pass astute legislation
议员必须草拟并通过有远见的法案、
that reflects today's technology
来反映今天的技术
and our notions of free and hate speech.
与我们对言论自由和仇恨言论的看法。
In New York recently, the law could not be applied to a perpetrator
纽约州现行诽谤法律，并不适用于仇恨言论，
because the crimes must have been committed --
因为法例规定那些言论
even if it was anonymous --
即使是匿名发表的—
they must have been committed by telephone, in mail,
必须以电话、书信，
by telegraph --
或是电报形式呈现。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
The language must be technologically neutral.
法律必须与时俱进。
So apparently,
你们看得出来
I've got a pretty bold voice.
我一向理直气壮。
So, let's talk about our friends ...
那么，让我们来谈谈我们的朋友。
white men.
白人男性。
You have a role to play and a choice to make.
你可以扮演一个角色，并可以做出选择。
You can do something,
你可以做一些事情，
or you can do nothing.
或者什么都不做。
We're cool in this room,
在这里很安全，
but when this goes out, everyone will say,
但当演讲传播出去时，每个人都会说，
"Oh my God, she's a reverse racist."
“我的天啊。她歧视白人。”
That quote was said by a white man, Robert Moritz,
这句话是由一个白人，罗伯特·弗罗斯特所说，
chairperson, PricewaterhouseCoopers,
普华永道的主席，
he asked me to include it in my talk.
他让我把它列入我的谈话中。
We need to grow support lines and help groups,
我们需要开发支持热线和帮助团体，
so victims can help each other
来让受害者可以在他们的生活和财政
when their lives and finances have been derailed.
被破坏的时候互相帮助。
We must as individuals disrupt gender violence as it is happening.
所有人必须合力制止针对女性的暴力
92 percent of young people 29 and under witness it.
29岁以下的年轻人当中，有 92% 曾目睹这种暴力，
72 percent of us have witnessed it.
我们之中的百分之72曾目睹过它。
We must have the courage and urgency
我们必须有勇气和紧迫感
to practice stopping it as it is unfolding.
在它的发展时制止它。
And lastly,
最后，
believe her.
相信她。
Believe her.
信任她。
(Applause)
（掌声）
This is fundamentally a problem of human interaction.
这是人类交流中得一个很根本问题。
And as I believe that human interaction is at the core of our healing,
我相信人际交流是我们愈合的精髓，
trauma not transformed will be trauma transferred.
伤痛未有治愈，就会传给他人。
Edith Wharton said, "The end is latent in the beginning,"
伊迪丝·华顿说，"结局在开头就潜伏着。"
so we are going to end this talk replacing hate speech with love speech.
所以我们要以关爱言论取代仇恨言论来结束这个演讲。
Because I get lonely in this,
因为我在这方面有时会感到孤独，
but I know that we are allies.
但我知道我们是盟友。
I recently learned
我最近学会了
about how gratitude and affirmations offset negative interactions.
凡事感恩、得到朋友肯定，可以抵销负面经历。
It takes five of those to offset one negative interaction,
五段正面经历才可抵销一段负面经历，
and gratitude in particular --
尤其是感恩——
free, available globally any time, anywhere,
无论何时何地、说何种语言，
to anyone in any dialect --
任何人都可以心怀感恩—，
it fires the pregenual anterior cingulate,
感恩可刺激大脑的前扣带回，
a watershed part of the brain
大脑的一个分水岭，
that floods it with great, good stuff.
这使它充满了伟大而美好的东西。
So I'm going to say awesome stuff about myself.
所以我会说有关我的一些了不起的事情。
I would like for you to reflect it back to me.
我希望你们能把它反馈给我。
It might sound something like this --
可能听起来像这样——
(Laughter)
（笑声）
I am a powerful and strong woman, and you would say, "Yes, you are."
我是一个强大而坚强的女人，你会说，“是的，你是。"
Audience: Yes, you are.
观众：是的,你是。
Ashley Judd: My mama loves me.
艾什莉·贾德：我的妈妈爱我。
A: Yes, she does.
观众：是的，她爱你。
AJ: I did a great job with my talk.
艾什莉·贾德：我做了一个出色的演讲。
A: Yes, you did.
观众：是的，你做到了。
AJ: I have a right to be here.
艾什莉·贾德：我有权力在这里。
A: Yes, you do.
观众：是的，你有。
AJ: I'm really cute.
艾什莉·贾德：我非常可爱。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
A: Yes, you are.
观众：是的，你很可爱。
AJ: God does good work.
艾什莉·贾德：上帝做善事。
A: Yes, He does.
观众：是的，他会做。
AJ: And I love you.
艾什莉·贾德：最后我爱你们。
Thank you so much for letting me be of service.
非常感谢你们让我为你们服务。
Bless you.
祝福你们。
(Applause)
（掌声）